Jorge E Navarro

12023 Fambridge Rd, Orlando, FL, 32837, US 407-965-6581 jorgeebn16@gmail.com www.linkedin.com/in/jorgeebn16

https://jorgeenavarro.com

Results-oriented professional with extensive experience in data analysis, web development, and quality control. Competent in interpreting data and developing Information System Development through the different development stages. Experienced in software testing, implementation, and documentation of changes. Excel at prioritizing business requirements and identifying process improvement opportunities. Possess diverse knowledge of software and processes Quality Assurance, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Jquery, Mongo DB, SQL, Python applications, and data visualization development.

Areas of Expertise

- Full Stack Web Development
- Data Analysis & Visualization
- · Quality Assurance

- Customer Service & Satisfaction
- Reports & Documentation
- Software Development
- Internal Auditing
- Problem Resolution
- · Team Building & Leadership

Career Experience

Inter Bio-Lab, Inc., Orlando, Florida

IT Manager 2010 – Present

Design, develop, implement, and coordinate company technology system policies, and procedures. Spearhead all aspects of IT department, comprising web designing, and database development. Plan, organize, control, and oversee IT and electronic data operations. Act in alignment with user requirements and system functionality, contributing to organizational policy.

- Managed Server Management and Server Administration including Control Access and User Domain Control.
- Identified potential issues and provided effective solutions.

E-Commerce Representative

2010 - Present

Direct all facets of organization consisting of publishing, products and sales management as well as customer interaction through multiple platforms including eBay, Amazon, DotMed, LabX, Medwow, and Kitmondo. Deliver knowledgeable answers to customer phone calls and e-mail inquiries regarding products and brand. Forge collaborative and positive working relationships with team members, clients, and senior management.

- Design of advertising documents and product promotions.
- Followed-up on all customer requests to ensure the brand provides highest level of customer service.
- Utilized CRM tools to manage ongoing client relationship.
- Played a significant role in assisting customers with after-sales service issues.

ISO Internal Auditor 2012 – 2018

Generation and publishing of Internal Audit Calendar and carried out regular internal audits based on the published calendar. Ensured audit cycle program remained effective and upgraded. Oversaw audit outcome and performed preventive/corrective actions. Verify that the solution proposed to resolve the preventive or corrective actions was appropriated and implemented. Meet with the external Auditor and present the result of the internal audit. Produced and submitted a full audit report to the management team.

Additional Experience

BOD/Corp Banca, Caracas-Venezuela

Quality Assurance Analyst

2007 – 2009

Responsible for Quality Assurance testing of new technological developments of the online banking platform (CorpLine), ATM and Point of Sales. As well testing in the banking platform of daily use in bank branches based on IBM Core Banking AS / 400 platform.

Technical Support Specialist (Internship), Corporación Alcaldía de Maracaibo, Venezuela

2006

Education

UCF Data Boot Camp (Full-Stack Web Development), UCF Continuing Education (Current)
UCF Data Boot Camp (Data Analytics & Visualization), UCF Continuing Education, 2020
Bachelor of Science in Computer Engineering, University Dr. Rafael Belloso Chacin—Venezuela, 2007

Technical Proficiencies

Microsoft Office, HTML, CSS, Javascript, Jquery, Mongo DB, SQL, JavaScript, Quality Assurace, Software Development, and Core Banking ISERIES AS400